in
learning to map and OpenStreetMap
introduction
not give campaign gives you an
understanding up why
open map data is important to people all
over the world
and why you should invest your time to
help create map data
online to OpenStreetMap da toward an
the OpenStreetMap task manager
the places most in need open map data
creation
maybe places that you've never been to
you that's okay
you can make a big difference simply by
treating roads
buildings and other features that you
can spot easily
from satellite imagery what in this
video tutorial
will show you how to map in
OpenStreetMap see you can start creating
open map data pas this video whenever
you need to you
and practice what you just land you can
also find written how-to instructions
under Step 2 on the map give learn to
map page
before you begin learning how to map
please make sure you have set up and
OpenStreetMap account
you can find instructions on how to do
that in step 1
on a map give learn to map page if you
have not signed up for OpenStreetMap
account yet
please posits video now and do so can
return here
to continue the tutorial
once you set up your OpenStreetMap
account the fine can really begin
you're about to learn the three main
things you can map in OpenStreetMap
points use to market place's lines
used to mark Rhodes impasse in areas
used to mark outlines at buildings
fields for any
other large area as you'll soon see
mapping is easy
and you can do it from anywhere in the
world even in places
that you've never been to you of in our
next steps
will look at OpenStreetMap and become
more familiar with it
you composites for the OEC any point to
review
and practice what you learned along the
way overview OpenStreetMap
to begin you log in to OpenStreetMap
once logged in you will see the map to
the right of the map
I the map controls you consume in zoom
out
and you your current location on the map
you can also select between layers
view the map key share the map I'm a
comment on a particular section
pas this video login and take a moment
to locate piece features
OpenStreetMap can return here to learn
to search
in soon in and out in OpenStreetMap
searching OpenStreetMap
is easy on the left side of the screen
is a search
area search for any location in the
world that you like
simply type the location and a new map
of the area
you selected will appear for now you
only need to know how to zoom in and
zoom out on the map
uses two min button on the right of the
screen
and examine the map you should be able
to see the three main elements a nap
points lines in areas pas this video
and take a moment to practice which is
you man and zoom out buttons
the search field and the three main
elements at the map
points lines in areas come back
to learn how to create points lines in
areas how to edit
OpenStreetMap to create points
lines areas in OpenStreetMap click on
the drop down
a row next to the word at the drop down
a route will give you a few options
select at it with ID in browser editor
there are several ways to edit and
create map data OpenStreetMap
for now the ID in browser editor
is the easiest to use because you will
not have to download anything to use it
it simply opens up in your Internet
browser after selecting
at it with ID in browser editor from the
drop down menu
the ID editor open you'll be able to
create map data
by adding points lines in areas please
pause this video now
open the ID in browser editor from the
drop down menu
and then come back to continue at the
top of the idea editor are the main
controls
you can select which action you'd like
to perform
map a point line or an area
the buttons to go back forward and save
are also at the top
by clicking Save after making an edit to
OpenStreetMap
your changes go live to the entire world
please remember to hit save often
there's also a dialog box to the left of
the map
this dialog box is where you will be
able to input information about the
points
lines and areas that you map it's okay
if you do not know the name of the place
Road or area just marking it on the map
so that the data exist
is very helpful for others who can add
in more detail
please pause this video for a moment and
get familiar with the various buttons
any ID editor walkthrough to the right
of the map
there's a help button you can click on
it anytime
to see valuable information answers to
questions that you might have about the
ID
editor there's also a walk-through which
will guide you through the process
editing and OpenStreetMap you can select
the walkthrough
as many times as you like you may have
completed the walkthrough
in OpenStreetMap when you signed up for
an account and logged in the first time
if you haven't already we recommend that
you posses
video and go through to walk through
getting started
once you complete the walk you the ID
editor
will still be open to continue with this
video tutorial
you need to pick in area to practice
napping in any place in the world will
work
and you don't have to pick a place you
have been to you or no well
an area with little existing map data is
best
so try practicing in a place that is not
a major city
are heavily developed area of course
you're welcome to practice not being in
an area that you are a no
this may be easier for you to start with
until you're comfortable mapping
how to make a point and OpenStreetMap of
to map a point in the OpenStreetMap ID
editor
simply click on the point button in the
top left at the map
it will turn blue to let you know that
it's been selected
then simply click on a position in the
map where there's a building
or area that you'd like to define a node
will appear
and also a dialog box
with the series descriptive options to
input will appear to the left of the map
if you know the name of the building or
area or additional details
you can enter them here when you mount
areas that you've never been to be four
you most likely won't know the names at
buildings roads
in areas that's OK too simply marking
point
is a huge help once you finish adding
details connected to the node
you can close the dialog box by clicking
on the ATX
at the top righted if you need to edit
the node
simply click on it again and the dialog
box will open
to delete and no that is incorrect or
was created by mistake
click on it a trash can icon will appear
next to it
click on the trash can and the node will
be removed remember
if you ever need to step back a few
edits click on the back arrow icon
at the top the editor you can also
stepped forward issue at its
with the forward a row icon remember
to save often please pass this video and
take a moment to practice mapping
appoint
return to this video when you're ready
to learn how to map
align how to mount a line and
OpenStreetMap
just as you click an appointment before
now click on the line but
at the top of the ID OpenStreetMap
editor
it will also turn blue to let you know
that it's been selected
now click on a position on the map a dot
will appear connected to align
click another point on the map and
another dot will appear
and the line will connect those two
point you can either continue to draw
more points
to establish the line or double-click on
the last point
to finish drying the line the line will
close red
to let you know that it has been created
a dialog box will open up to the left of
the map
editor you can specify whether the line
is a road
path River for any other number options
you can be very specific or general
depending on what you can determine from
the satellite imagery
to modify line that has already been
created simply click on it
the dialog box will open next to the
editor along with the trash can icon
next to the line click Save to make sure
you're at it are logged into the
OpenStreetMap data base
please pass this video and take a moment
to practice mapping the line
return to this video when you're ready
to learn to map an area
how to map in area in OpenStreetMap an
area can I do be a park
a building in Lake a forest or any other
number of things
it's up to you to define on the map just
as with points and lines
click on the area button at the top of
the editor
it will turn blue to let you know that
you selected
once you've done that select the edges
and the building our feature you want to
be fine
just click on the corners any editor
will fill in the space
in between once you fully outlined what
you want
double-click on the last created point
to complete the area
the area will turn red to let you know
that it's been created
in a dialog box will appear
next to the map editor and allow you to
label the area you just defined
there are numerous options and you can
be as specific
or general as you like depending on what
information you know
again it is okay if you don't know to
specific name in the area
you can leave this section blank as you
will most likely not know the exact
names at the areas being mapped
just label what you can see from the
satellite imagery such as a lake
or building what also always remember to
hit save
at the top the editor please pass this
video
and take a moment to practice mapping
closing
that's it that's all it takes to start
mapping and OpenStreetMap
once you hit save your at its our lives
and park at the OpenStreetMap data base
which is immediately available to anyone
in the world
once you feel confident mapping continue
to the next video
to learn how to select a task from the
OpenStreetMap task manager
of
and
go